var readline = require('readline');
var rl = readline.createInterface({
    input: process.stdin,
    output: process.stdout
});
var totalQuestions = 10;
var passingGrade = 50;
var maxGrade = 100;
var scoreRange = {
    smart: 90,
    good: 80,
    ok: 70,
    pass: 60,
    tryAgain: 59
};
var questions = [
    { question: 'What is 1 + 1?', correctAnswer: '2' },
    { question: 'What is 2 + 2?', correctAnswer: '4' },
    { question: 'What is 3 + 3?', correctAnswer: '6' },
    { question: 'What is 4 + 4?', correctAnswer: '8' },
    { question: 'What is 5 + 5?', correctAnswer: '10' },
    { question: 'What is 6 + 6?', correctAnswer: '12' },
    { question: 'What is 7 + 7?', correctAnswer: '14' },
    { question: 'What is 8 + 8?', correctAnswer: '16' },
    { question: 'What is 9 + 9?', correctAnswer: '18' },
    { question: 'What is 10 + 10?', correctAnswer: '20' }
];
var score = 0;
var attempts = 0;
var messages = {
    good: ['Very good!', 'Excellent!', 'Nice work!', 'Keep up the good work!'],
    wrong: ['No. Please try again.', 'Wrong. Try once more.', 'No. Donâ€™t give up!', 'Not correct. Keep trying.']
};
function askQuestion(index) {
    rl.question("".concat(questions[index].question, " "), function (answer) {
        if (answer === questions[index].correctAnswer) {
            score += 10;
            console.log(messages.good[Math.floor(Math.random() * messages.good.length)]);
            attempts = 0;
        }
        else {
            attempts++;
            if (attempts < 3) {
                console.log(messages.wrong[Math.floor(Math.random() * messages.wrong.length)]);
                askQuestion(index);
            }
            else {
                console.log('Incorrect answer, moving to next question.');
                attempts = 0;
            }
        }
        if (index + 1 < questions.length) {
            askQuestion(index + 1);
        }
        else {
            console.log('All questions completed!');
            gradeStudent();
        }
    });
}
function gradeStudent() {
    var finalMessage = '';
    if (score >= scoreRange.smart) {
        finalMessage = 'SMART';
    }
    else if (score >= scoreRange.good) {
        finalMessage = 'GOOD';
    }
    else if (score >= scoreRange.ok) {
        finalMessage = 'OK';
    }
    else if (score >= scoreRange.pass) {
        finalMessage = 'PASS';
    }
    else {
        finalMessage = 'TRY AGAIN';
    }
    console.log("Your score: ".concat(score, " - Result: ").concat(finalMessage));
    rl.close();
}
askQuestion(0);
